pwc.in 2017-06-13

# PwC privacy statement

## Introduction

This privacy statement applies to the collection, process, disclosure and use of personal identifiable information (PII) or the personal sensitive information (PSI), as the case may be, which is submitted to PricewaterhouseCoopers Private Limited (a limited liability company in India having Corporate Identity Number or CIN: U74140WB1983PTC036093), having its registered office at Y-14, Block EP, Sector V, Salt Lake, Kolkata – 700091 (‘PwC’ or ‘we’). PwC is an Indian member firm of PricewaterhouseCoopers International Limited (PwCIL), each member firm of which is a separate legal entity.

PwC is committed to maintaining the privacy and integrity of PII and PSI and this privacy statement describes PwC’s approach on addressing all such issues. This privacy statement provides details about the types of personal information that we collect, how we use, process, protect and disclose such personal information and the rights individuals have to control our usage and disclosure of such personal information. Personal information submitted may be transferred to other individual PricewaterhouseCoopers firms, which are member firms of the PricewaterhouseCoopers global network of separate member firms (each of which is a separate and independent legal entity), where it is necessary to meet the purpose for which the user has submitted the information. By using this site and submitting any personal information, you agree to the use and disclosure by PwC of such information in accordance with this privacy statement.

## Data collection 

We may collect personal information from clients, customers, employees, contractors and other individuals. We collect such information when it is necessary for business purposes. Usually, we collect information like the contact details and organisational roles of our clients, suppliers and other business contacts. Typically, this information includes names, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses and job titles. In the course of providing professional services to our clients, we may need to collect more detailed personal information (for instance, financial details if we are engaged to perform financial or tax services).

Through this website, we only collect PII or PSI that is specifically and voluntarily provided by visitors having regard to the purpose for its disclosure. PwC receives limited personal information, such as name, title, company address, email address, and telephone and fax numbers from website visitors. Demographic information, including gender and occupation, is not actively sought, but may be submitted when a visitor responds to an online job application or registers for our alumni programme. It is our policy to limit the information collected to only the minimum information required to complete a visitor's request. Visitors are also able to send email through this site. Their messages will contain the user's screen name and email address, as well as any additional information the user may wish to include in the message. Because we use the website as a recruiting tool, a visit to the website may also result in the user sending a resume to an individual within PwC which may contain more detailed information.

## Use of personal information 

The main purposes of collecting personal information about individuals are as follows:

  * Providing services
  * Respond to an individual’s request
  * Maintaining contact with clients
  * Keeping clients and other contacts informed of the services we offer and industry developments that may be of interest to them, and to notify them of service offerings, seminars and other events we organise
  * General management and reporting purposes, such as invoicing and account management
  * Recruitment of staff and providing internal services to them
  * All other lawful purposes related to our business and in furtherance to fulfilment of lawful contract.

Personal information collected by us through this site is used only for the intended purpose stated at the time that the information is collected or for the purposes specified above.

## Disclosure of personal information 

We do not routinely disclose or transfer an individual’s personal information to other organisations unless we have the prior and specific permission of the individual or the entity that provided such information on behalf of such individuals or unless:

  * such disclosure or transfer is permitted under this privacy statement or the disclosure or transfer required by law, including for the purpose of compliance with subpoenas, court orders, requests or order from legal authorities or law enforcement agencies requiring such disclosure;
  * we believe it necessary to provide the individual with a product or services which it has requested (or, in the case of a partner or employee of PwC, if it is related or necessary to maintain that person’s role at PwC);
  * such disclosure is required to help investigate, prevent or take action regarding unlawful and illegal activities, suspected fraud, economic offences, potential threat to the safety or security of any person, violations of website terms of use or to defend against legal claims; or
  * the disclosure is required for us to use or process the data for the purpose for which it was obtained.

Except as set out in this privacy statement or specifically allowed under law, we will not disclose, share, sell or rent an individual’s personal information to any third party. If an individual wishes to update or change any information, he or she may do so by requesting to us and we will prospectively cease to use or modify his or her personal information.

We use a range of service providers and contractors to help us maximise the quality and efficiency of our services and our business operations (including internal business requirements). This means that third-party individuals and organisations may sometimes have access to personal information held by PwC and may collect it from, process or use it on behalf of PwC. We require our service providers and contractors to be under appropriate confidentiality requirements, maintain adequate technical and network security and not to use or disclose such information for any unauthorised purposes.

## Transfer of personal information outside India 

As part of a global network of PricewaterhouseCoopers firms, PwC exchanges or may need to exchange information, including personal information within the network or with other overseas service providers/contractors working and acting on behalf of the member firm of the network. As a result, we may transfer personal information outside India to other countries whose privacy laws provide different level of protection. PwC may also use overseas facilities to process, host or back up its information. As a result, we may need to transfer personal information to our overseas facilities for these purposes. However, any such information transferred shall be subject to appropriate data protection obligations.

## Cookies and log files 

Cookies may be used on some pages of our websites. Cookies are small text files placed on a visitor’s hard drive that assist us in providing a more customised website experience. For example, a cookie can be used to store registration information in an area of the site so that a user does not need to re-enter it on subsequent visits to that area. It is PwC's policy to use cookies to make navigation of our websites easier for visitors and to facilitate efficient registration procedures. Site statistics are compiled by third parties, and therefore the visitor’s IP address will be passed to third parties for statistical reporting only. Cookies are primarily used to enhance the visitor’s online experience and are not used to track the navigational habits of identified visitors, unless we obtain the visitor’s specific and prior written permission to do so. If a visitor is concerned about cookies, most browsers permit individuals to decline cookies. In most cases, a visitor may refuse a cookie and still fully navigate our websites; however, other functionality in the site may be impaired. After termination of the visit to our site, a visitor can always delete the cookie from his or her system if he or she wishes. In order to properly manage our website we may anonymously log information on our operational systems and identify categories of visitors by items such as domains and browser types. These statistics are reported in the aggregate to our webmasters. This is to ensure that our website enhances the web experience for visitors and is an effective information resource.

## Personal information retention 

Some of the information we receive is not retained. Contact information about visitors (such as information generated though registration for access to areas on the site) will be kept as long as the information is required for the purposes for which it was collected or until a user requests that we delete that information or as required by law. Mailing list information, discussion posts and email are kept for only the period of time considered reasonable to facilitate the visitor's requests. Information that is kept by us will be destroyed or deleted after a reasonable period from the time when it becomes outdated or is no longer required. We may, however, need to retain copies of information (which may include personal information) for internal record-keeping purposes and/or for compliance with applicable law or professional standards, whose requirements may be more than that of laws and rules requiring data protection and privacy.

## Choices 

Personal information including sensitive personal information provided to PwC through its website is provided voluntarily by visitors. Should visitors subsequently choose to withdraw their consent in respect of their personal information, unsubscribe from mailing lists or any registrations, we will provide instructions on the appropriate website area or in communications to our visitors. Alternatively, PwC executive directors, staff and third parties can also report concerns through the Global Helpline website www.pwc.com/ethics by clicking on 'Contact us'.

## Access 

When requested and practical, each individual has the right of access to personal information they have submitted to PwC. We do not assume responsibility for verifying the ongoing accuracy of the content of personal information. We are committed to providing reasonable and practical access to users to allow them the opportunity to identify and correct any inaccuracies. When requested and practical, PwC will arrange to delete personal information from current operational systems.

## Security 

PwC has implemented generally accepted standards of technology and operational security in order to protect personal information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. We follow a network-wide security policy. Only authorised personnel are provided access to sensitive personal information and these personnel have agreed to maintain confidentiality, security and integrity of this information. While PwC follows the standard industry practices and takes reasonable security measures to protect the personal information under our control, information may be disclosed through any unlawful or unauthorised access or regulatory environment and measures or interception of transmissions or private communications and other users and third parties may abuse or misuse an individual’s personal information. We disclaim all liability for error in transmissions and unauthorised access or interceptions, abuse or misuse by third parties and other users.

## Third-party links 

Our websites may contain links to other websites operated by third parties. Please note that this privacy statement applies only to the personal information that we collect through our websites or otherwise in the course of our business dealings, and we cannot be responsible for personal information that third parties may collect, store and use through their websites which an individual may access after clicking the links that may be provided on our websites. An individual should always carefully read the privacy policy of each website they visit even if some of them may be listed as microsite to main PwC site.

## Modifications 

PwC reserves the right to modify or amend this statement at any time with or without notice for legal, administrative and technical reasons. The effective date will be displayed at the beginning of this statement.

## Grievance officer 

If an individual has any questions or grievances regarding anything covered by this privacy statement, he or she can contact the grievance officer on the toll-free helpline (1-800-209-6005).

If an individual has any queries about our privacy practices or the implementation thereof or notice any discrepancy in our database relating to the individual, he or she may address such matters to [ethics.india@in.pwc.com](mailto:ethics.india@in.pwc.com).
